我丈夫和我节衣缩食过了很多年
My husband and I scrimped and saved for so many years.
为了不成为家庭的负担
We did our best to build a nest egg
我们尽力攒下了一笔养老金
so that we wouldn't be a burden to our family.
罗纳德去世后  我搬进了一家生活协助中心
After Ronald passed, I moved to an assisted-living facility --
很不错的地方
a nice place.
他们说会照顾好一切
They told me they'd take care of everything,
但有一天  他们说我一分钱都没了
but then, one day, they said all my money was gone.
怎么会这样
How could that be?
钱都去哪儿了
Where did it all go?
如果你或爱人
If you or a loved one
是矶鹞渡生活协助中心
is a resident of a Sandpiper crossing facility
或是其他有关退休社区的居民
or other associated retirement community...
天啊  你自己配的音吗
Jesus. ‭You used your own voice?
你也许有资格
...You may be eligible to
-获得补偿  -为了省钱
- receive compensation. - Strictly to save money.
-总共才花了  -行了
- All in, the whole thing cost -- - Just --
如需免费咨询
For a free consultation,
请致电戴维斯梅因律所
call the law offices of Davis & Main
电话505-242-7700
at 505-242-7700.
That's 505-242-7700.
制作成本总共才647美元
The production costs -- $647, all in.
播出一次的广告费才七百  便宜到家了
The one single airing was a $700 ad buy, so dirt-cheap.
你觉得这是因为钱吗
You think this is about money?
我们找你来是因为钱吗
You think that's what this is about?
我只是尽量提供全面的信息
I'm just trying to offer complete information here.
这次播出  只是一个实验
Now, this one airing -- it was an experiment,
而且不管怎么说  都是一次成功的实验
and as such, by any measure, a success.
你一直说"实验实验"
You keep using the word "Experiment"
好像你是该死的莱特兄弟似的
like you're ‭the goddamned Wright brothers.
你到底准备什么时候告诉我们这个"实验"
When exactly were you gonna tell us about this experiment?
今天
Today.
就今早
This morning.
我承认我有点操之过急了
I-I admit, I got a little ahead of myself,
有点过于激动了
a little...exuberant.
我为此道歉
And for that, I apologize.
但我认为最重要的是
But the headline here is -- I think --
广告播出后我们已经接到将近两百通来电了
we've gotten nearly 200 phone calls since this one airing.
克利福德  昨晚我俩聊过后
Cliff, since you and I spoke last night,
又多了七十二通
72 more.
听到了吗  外面响起的就是胜利的号角
You hear that? Right there -- that's the sound of victory.
吉米  别自圆其说了
Jimmy, stop selling.
别装作对真正的问题视而不见
And don't act like ‭you don't see the problem here.
我没觉得有问题啊
I don't.
你不跟我们打招呼
You cut us out.
绕过我们自行其是
You did an end run around us.
"过于激动"才不是什么借口
Exuberance is no excuse.
克利福德
Cliff.
客户联系由我负责
Client outreach is my department.
你第一天就跟我说清楚了
Now, you told me that from day one.
吉米  那如果我让你负责发工资
Jimmy, if I put you in charge of payroll, would that mean
那你给每个人发一百万奖金我都得同意咯
I'd be okay with you giving everyone a million-dollar bonus?
我俩讨论过广告的可行性啊
You and I did discuss the possibility of a commercial.
理论上的可行性而已
The possibility in the abstract,
而且还是我出门前的短短三十秒内谈的
for a grand total of 30 seconds when I was halfway out the door.
我还以为我听出了你的热情
I guess -- I thought I heard enthusiasm,
所以我就稍微自作主张了点
so I-I took some initiative.
"稍微"
"Some."
戴维斯梅因是个团队
We are a team at Davis & Main.
讲究的是团队合作
This is a team approach.
你来之前还是个独立从业者
You coming to us ‭as a solo practitioner --
我知道你还需要一段时间的学习
I knew there was gonna be a learning curve.
但如果你就是学不会融入这个团队
But if you simply can't fit in as part of the team --
我可以融入  我融入了啊
I can fit in. I-I fit in.
我是来帮你们和HHM打赢矶鹞渡的官司的
I am here to help you and HHM win Sandpiper.
所以我才会这么做
That's all this was about.
我们可没指望着矶鹞渡过活
Sandpiper's not what keeps the lights on around here.
我们有的客户不想跟这种...东西
We have clients who wouldn't want to be associated
联系在一起
with this kind of... this.
我们的形象和名誉
Our image, our reputation
是我们小心经营多年才打造起来的
is something we've been carefully building for years.
比任何案子都重要
It's worth far more than any one case.
这样的行为会损害名誉
Something like this could damage it.
这么说吧
Suffice it to say,
现在我们几位都对你没什么好感
there's not a lot of love for you in the room at the moment.
投票结果二比一  要因为你的不当行为解雇你
The vote is currently two to one to fire you for cause.
不过
However...
我相信要给人第二次机会
I believe in second chances.
但是再犯一次就三振出局
But know this is both strike one and strike two.
三振出局法
有两次犯罪前科的罪犯第三次犯罪时从重量刑
今后你将受到更严格的监督
Going forward, you can expect a great deal more scrutiny.
快接  快接
Come on. Come on.
你好
Hello.
这是金·韦克斯勒的语音信箱
You've reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
请留言
Please leave me a message,
我会尽快回复你
And I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
金
Hey, kim.
尽快打给我  好吗
I need you to call me as soon as you can, all right?
时间很关键
It's a time-sensitive thing, so, uh,
我是说  我可能...
I mean, I may have, uh, just --
麻烦你在跟霍华德谈之前打给我好吗
Well, please call me before you talk to Howard, okay?
再见
Bye.
未接来电
一条语音消息
很简单的问题  金
It's a simple question, Kim --
你知不知道这条广告
Did you or did you not know about this commercial?
我知道
I -- yes.
他给我看了
He showed it to me.
他给你看了吗
He showed it to you?
是的  几天前
Yes. A few days ago.
这事儿你没跟任何人说吗
And you didn't say anything to anyone?
没有
No. I didn't.
你不觉得该跟我说一声吗
You didn't think I deserved a heads-up?
我没想到
I didn't realize --
当时我觉得没必要
At the time, ‭I didn't think it was necessary.
那你想错了
Well, you were wrong about that.
我们被合伙律师问了个措手不及
We were caught flat-footed in front of our co-counsel,
不用我跟你解释  这对HHM的影响很不好
which I don't need to tell you, does not reflect well on HHM.
对你也不好
Or on you.
就这样吧
That'll be all.
你可以走了
You can go.
你准备怎么办
What are you going to do?
你觉得呢
So, what do you think?
我觉得从这里可以很清楚地观察对面
I figure from here, you've got a good bead on the place,
但里面的人  他们发现不了你
but someone inside -- they can't pick you out.
屠库和我  就在那里
Tuco and me -- that's our spot.
他总是面朝外坐着
He always sits facing out,
把场面搞得像黑帮一样
makes it look like it's a gangster thing,
但他是为了盯着自己的车
but I know it's just so he can keep an eye on his ride.
每个周二  我们都来这里收账
Every Tuesday, ‭we're here squaring accounts.
毒贩子过来  付掉欠款
Dealer comes in, pays what he owes.
屠库  他喜欢跟他们面对面
Tuco -- he likes to get face-to-face.
他说他想知道的一切都写在脸上
Says everything he needs to know is written right here.
看着他们的眼睛
Looks 'em in the eyes.
死盯着  好像要把他们看穿
Just stares, like he's looking inside of 'em.
我见过他一盯就盯上五分钟十分钟
I've seen him go like that 5, 10 minutes.
为什么要那么做
And what does that accomplish?
他把这叫做测谎仪
Calls it his lie detector.
所以这事得持续一整天
That's why these things go all day.
就你俩吗  没帮手了吗
Just the two of you? No extra muscle?
不需要  我们自己能搞定
Don't need it. ‭We can handle our business.
不过得花好几个钟头
Anyway, it takes hours.
收钱  数钱  测谎
Collect the cash, count it, lie detector.
一次进来一个  交易  然后下一个
One at a time -- guy comes in, transacts, then the next.
完事之后  屠库上他的车  我上我的
Then, when we're done, Tuco gets in his car, I get in mine.
然后各走各的
Boom. We go our separate ways.
这时候就该你上了
That is where you come in.
当你看到他在收拾了  就开过去
You see him packing up -- wsssh -- drive over.
停在屠库旁边的车位
Pull up in the spot next to Tuco's.
砰  爆头
Pop. Head shot.
开车走人  很简单
Roll out. Easy.
40号公路的上匝道就在那边八个街区外
I-40 onramp is eight blocks up.
别人还没反应过来  你就已经没了踪影
You're in the wind ‭before anyone has time to blink.
更好的是  这些毒贩子
And here's the beauty -- all these, um, dealers?
都知道我们在这  所以故事可以这么编
They know we're here, so the story is,
他们其中一个想要杀死屠库
one of them got ideas, decided to kill Tuco,
从这生意中捞一笔
get a cut of the business.
在贩毒集团看来  可能是任何一个人
Could've been any of them, as far as the cartel's concerned.
这些星期二
These Tuesdays of yours --
结束的时候是白天还是晚上
Day or night when you wrap it up?
-白天  -所以就是光天化日
- Day. - ‭So, full daylight.
过往车辆也很多
Plenty of traffic.
我怎样才能不被看见呢
How exactly do I not get seen?
我的车总会被看见吧
My car, at least.
墨菲定律告诉我  有人会记下车牌的
Murphy's Law tells me somebody's gonna pull a plate.
会出错的  终将出错
好吧  那就去车场买辆旧车
Fine. ‭Go to the yard. Buy a beater.
你就待在车里
You're gonna stay in the car.
没人会看见你
‭Ain't no one gonna see you.
就算看到你了  那又怎样
And if they do see you, so what?
这就是你为什么是完美人选
That's why you're perfect.
你很不起眼  没谁也没联系
You're no one. You got no connections.
你就是个幽灵
You're a ghost.
所以我停在他旁边
So, I pull in next to him --
那得假定有停车的地方
That assumes there's a parking spot.
毒贩子都停在他车旁边
Our guys park next to him.
来去都是同一个车位
They come and go from the same spot.
最后一个人走了  你就可以上了
Last one takes off, you're open.
要是有人停在我后面  我就被堵了
Someone comes in behind me, I'm blocked.
谁会停在你后面啊
Who's gonna pull in behind you?
来吃玉米卷饼的人
Well, I'm guessing someone who likes tacos.
那该怎么办
What then?
我该怎么离开
What's my exit?
不知道
I don't know.
下车跑路
Get out and run.
我膝盖不好
Bad knees.
我付钱就是让你搞定这些细节的
Look, the details -- that's what I'm paying you for.
你要是有更好的计划  请告诉我
You've got a better plan, go on, tell me.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
你确定要这么干吗
You sure about this?
杀死你的同伙
Killing your partner --
干了就没有回头路了
that's a bell you don't un-ring.
看到了吗
See this?
你知道这是怎么弄的吗
You know how I got this?
九六  九七年的时候  屠库和我
Back in '96, '97, Tuco and I
和一群河滨县的飞车党合作
were working with these bikers out of Riverside County.
他们卖低纯度冰毒
They were running ‭this peanut-butter crank --
质量次得很
Real shit, y'know?
但是便宜  我们拿到手很快就卖完了
But cheap, and we could sell it as fast as we got it.
后来屠库也用上了
Anyway, ‭Tuco develops a taste for it.
这毒品把人变得很坏
And crank does not bring out the best in people.
让屠库发疯
Made Tuco erratic.
我们的联络人是一个叫道格·保尔森的人
Our connect ‭was a guy called Dawg Paulson.
有一天  屠库和道格见面
One day, ‭Tuco's settling up with Dawg.
决定对他测测谎
He decides ‭to put on his lie detector.
道格说"你要干嘛"
Dawg's like, ‭"What the hell?" You know.
屠库就一直死盯着他
Tuco just keeps staring at him.
然后他就不说话了
Then he goes real quiet.
"你觉得我是傻逼吗  道格"
"You think I'm an idiot, Dawg?"
他认为道格在给他的竞争对手供货
He thinks Dawg is supplying his competitor,
想要把屠库踢出去
trying to cut Tuco out.
道格矢口否认
Dawg -- he denies it.
"不可能  不是我"
"No way! Not me!"
屠库都没有提高嗓门  但突然间
Tuco doesn't even ‭raise his voice, but suddenly,
他掏出削短霰弹枪
he's got a sawed-off and...
一枪崩了道格的脸
right in Dawg's face.
我就站在他身后
I was behind him.
那是我至今为止见过最恶心的画面
Sickest thing I ever saw, to this day.
而这
And this?
是道格的头骨碎片
A piece of Dawg's skull --
一小块钻到皮肤下面去了
Under the skin, a little piece of him.
我试过挖出来  但它就是不肯出来
I tried digging it out, but it's in there pretty good.
这事可不能去找医生
Anyway, not the kinda thing you go to the doctor's for.
其实我想说  屠库很喜欢道格
The thing about it was, Tuco really liked dawg.
后来他也有点后悔
Kind of felt bad afterwards.
但当他吸了毒  就疯了
But when he's using, loco, crazy.
根本无法形容
There's no other way to put it.
现在他又开始吸毒了
And he's using again.
纯度更高的  劲儿更大
Crystal -- much bigger kick.
所以跟你说的一样
So... It's like you said.
如果屠库发现了我在外面的私活儿
If Tuco finds out about my, y'know, independent ventures,
我就会落得跟道格一样的下场
it's gonna be Dawg all over again.
有我没他
It's him or me.
那里
There.
用装了瞄准器的枪就可以击中
A man with a scoped rifle could get a clean shot.
就一发子弹
Fire a single round,
在有人反应过来之前消失
disappear before anybody knew what had happened.
没有目击者  还可以顺利逃脱
No witnesses. Clean egress.
很远啊
Pretty far.
你打得中吗
You can make that shot?
打得中
Yeah.
你同意干了吗
You saying you'll do it?
五万
50 grand?
那就五万
50 grand.
我会办好的
I'll look into it.
你哥哥不在这  麦吉尔先生
Your brother isn't here, Mr. Mcgill.
我知道
I know.
他让我来拿他的吸墨纸
Uh, he sent me to get his ink blotter.
-就一会  -小心点
- I'll just be a second. - ‭Watch yourself.
地很滑
The floor's slick.
多谢  杰苏阿尔多
Oh, thank you, Gesualdo.
抱歉踩脏了
Sorry about the floor!
不是吧
Oh, no.
你在找韦克斯勒小姐吗
Are you looking for Ms. Wexler?
没赶上  是吧
I guess I'm too late, huh?
不  她还没走
No, she's still here.
在哪
Where?
金
Kim.
我非常  非常抱歉
I am so, so sorry.
我昨晚就应该告诉你的
I should have told you last night.
是吗
You think?
我真以为我能解决的
I honestly thought I could fix it.
我以为他们一看到数字就懂了
I thought they'd understand once they saw the numbers.
我知道广告会有用  也确实如此
I knew it would work, and it did.
真的有效
It worked.
霍华德不能因为我做的事
Howard can't just stick you in doc review
就把你弄来复审文件
because of something I did.
而且我俩在两家不同的律所
Plus, at an ‭entirely different law firm.
完全没有道理啊
What the hell kind of sense does that make?!
我告诉过你后果就是这样
I told you this would happen.
他不能因为这事怪你
He can't blame you for this.
我警告过你他会的
I warned you he would.
我要去找霍华德
I'm talking to Howard.
干什么  再骂他是卑鄙无耻的猪吗
What? And call him a pig fucker again?
是啊  会有用的
Yeah, that'll help.
我搞砸了
I screwed up, you know?
我知道
I know that.
但这...  这完全是扯淡
But this -- this is total B.S.!
我今晚就去找他谈
I'm -- ‭I'm talking to him tonight!
吉米别去  你只会弄得更糟
Jimmy, no. ‭You'd only make things worse.
-我会向他解释  -不用
- I'll explain it to him. - ‭No!
我不是请求你  而是告诉你
I'm not asking you -- I'm telling you.
如果你去找霍华德  你和我就没戏了
If you go to Howard, you and I -- we're done.
那我们现在还有戏吗
So, we're not done now?
我需要这份工作
I need this job.
我还有大约四十个小时的收费指标没完成
And there's a weekly billing quota that I'm about 40 hours behind on,
所以可以请你离开吗
so could you please just go?
对不起
I'm sorry.
查克
Chuck!
快开门
Come on!
我不会走的
I'm not going away!
好  你自找的
All right, you asked for it!
我进来了
I'm comin' in!
查克
Chuck?
能听见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
能说话吗
Can you talk to me?
要我送你去医院吗
Do you want me ‭to get you to the hospital?
不  不去医院
No. No hospitals.
我会好的
I'll -- I'll be all right.
请给我点水
Get some water, please.
给你额外的保护
Extra protection here.
给  这样
Here. You know what?
坐起来
Sit up.
你能坐起来吗
Can you sit?
好的
All right.
好了
Okay. All right.
拿着
Here.
这是阿玛利特AR-50狙击步枪
That's the Armalite AR-50 --
制造技术先进  精确范围两千四百米
State of the art, ‭accurate to 2,400 meters.
装备了里奥波特Mark4瞄准镜
I got the Leupold Mark 4 on it now,
但我可以帮你升级到施密特本德的
but I can always upgrade you to a Schmidt & Bender.
手动单发
Single shot, bolt.
简单  有效  值得信赖
Simple, effective, reliable.
用的是0.50直径的子弹
It fires the .50-caliber BMG --
对轻型掩体内的软目标很有效
Very effective against soft targets in light cover --
可以射穿汽车  小树等等
behind cars, ‭small-diameter trees, and such.
与往常一样  我已经特意
As always, I've gone to the trouble
磨掉了序列号
of grinding down the serial number.
除非你彻底磨个洞
Well, unless you ‭ground a hole clean through,
否则用酸都可以复原
acid will recover it.
说得没错
Well, that would be true,
但我又用随机点刻压力机做了处理
but I follow up with a pass through ‭a random-stipple machine press.
把它藏在金属密度中
Hides the patterns in the metal density.
应该可以逃过X射线衍射
Should throw off your X-ray diffraction
还有其他高科技手段的检测
and some other higher-end methods.
当然万事无完美  但这枪接近完美了
Nothing's perfect, of course, but this is close.
就像疝气上装了个瞄准镜
Looks like a hernia with a scope on it.
三十四磅
34 pounds,
不包括你的枪架  那也会增加重量
not including your bipod, which adds some heft.
太重了
Too much gun.
我同意  对于大多数场合确实重
For most applications, I would tend to agree.
SR-25比赛步枪  尤金·斯通勒设计  半自动
SR-25 match rifle -- Eugene Stoner design, semi-auto.
大概十一磅
That's about 11 pounds there.
没有AR-50的射程和穿透力
Not quite the range or the punch of the AR-50,
但射程就算超过一千米
but you're still talking about a .5 M.O.A.
射击精度也高达0.5MOA
at well past 1,000 meters.
我听说容易卡壳
I've heard they're prone to jam.
在实战中确实发生过
Well, it's been known to happen in the field,
但没有一把半自动步枪可以自吹不卡壳的
but there's not a semi-auto built can boast it never jams.
如果你有所顾虑  你应该选择手动式的
If that's a concern, you ought to stick to bolts.
好的手动步枪如果都能卡壳
Good bolt-action rifle -- if you jammed it,
那我打赌你肯定是故意的
I'd wager ‭you were setting out to do so.
我们来看看这把M40
Which brings us to the M40 --
十分可靠  经过战斗检验
Tried and true, battle-tested.
自从1966年
Essentially, the same rifle
海军陆战队狙击手就用这种枪了
used by marine snipers since 1966.
轻便精准  适合在八百到一千二百米之内
It's light, accurate, good for soft targets
射击软目标
in the 800- to 1,2000-meter range.
看起来你了解这把枪
You seem to know this one.
那当然
Oh, yeah.
可以这么说
You could say that.
那是A1型
That's the A1 model.
在原版基础上变化不大
There's not much change from the original.
最大的不同在于枪托
Biggest difference is the stock --
不是木制的  改成玻璃纤维了
it's fiberglass instead of wood.
1970年左右改的
It changed it over in 1970 or so.
好的  木头太容易变形
Good. Wood warped like hell.
要是受了潮  又被曝晒  就完了
You get it wet, ‭you put it in the sun -- gone.
这枪被带到该死的丛林里使用之前
Somebody probably ‭should've figured that out
那些人真该想到这点
before they sent it into a damn jungle.
是应该想到
Yeah. Probably.
如果这些都不喜欢
If these aren't to your liking,
我可以再弄几支来
I could get my hands on a few more.
不用了
No.
我改主意了
I've changed my mind.
谢谢
Thank you.
这次我不需要枪
I don't need anything at this time.
麻烦你了
For your trouble.
不用客气
Oh, it's no trouble.
我做的都是回头生意
I make my living on repeat business.
等你有需要  就来找我
When you need what I'm offering, you know how to find me.
你还在这啊
You're still here.
是的  我还在
Yeah, I'm still here.
你睡觉了吗
Did you get any sleep?
睡了一会
Some.
足够了
Enough.
你感觉怎么样
‭How you feeling?
我想喝点茶
I could use some tea.
谢谢
Thanks.
你昨晚吓到我了
‭You scared me last night.
是啊  有时候会这样
Yeah. Happens sometimes.
有时候是我太过火了  仅此而已
Sometimes, I overdo it -- that's all.
都会好的
It passes.
去办公室把你累得筋疲力竭吧
Going into the office really takes it out of you, doesn't it?
如果待得太久  是很累
If I stay too long, yeah.
大概是走不开吧
Guess it's hard not to stay.
毕竟有那么多重要的事要你来做
There's so many important things for you to do there --
比如惩罚金·韦克斯勒
like, you know, stick it to Kim Wexler.
我对金·韦克斯勒做什么了
What did I do to Kim Wexler?
她又回"玉米地"了  不是吗
She's back in the cornfield, isn't she?
我什么都没对金做
I didn't do anything to Kim.
我当时确实在场
I mean, I was present, yes.
但是人事管理的决策都是霍华德做的
But management of personnel -- those decisions are all Howard's.
可笑
That is rich.
那你告诉我
But tell me,
霍华德做"管理决策"的时候
when Howard was makin' his "management decisions,"
是坐在你膝盖上  你把手伸进他屁眼了吗
was he sitting on your knee with your arm up his ass?
把霍华德比作戴在手上的布偶
你喝水的时候他是不是都说不出话
Hey, can he talk while you drink a glass of water?
你简直没有道理
That's uncalled-for.
如果霍华德是我的布偶
And if howard were my puppet,
他才不会推荐你去戴维斯梅因律所
he certainly wouldn't have recommended you to Davis & Main.
实际上  我确定是金·韦克斯勒
Actually, I'm sure it was Kim Wexler
说服他这样做的  所以他才生气
who talked him into doing that. Hence his anger.
别惩罚金
Don't punish Kim.
如果你生我的气  那就冲我来
If you're mad at me, take it out on me.
你觉得整个世界都围着你转  吉米
I know you like to think the world revolves around you, Jimmy,
但这和你无关
but this has nothing to do with you.
金对哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所负责
Kim had a responsibility to Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
她本该为自己律所的利益着想
She should have been looking out for her firm's interests.
没告诉我们你要干什么是她的错
Not letting us know what you were up to was her mistake.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你不能为这事生她的气
You can't be pissed off at her about this.
我没生气
I'm not.
霍华德才生气
Howard is.
他凭什么不生气呢
And why shouldn't he be?
因为她不知道
Because she didn't know.
她不知道我会播出广告
She didn't know I was gonna air the commercial.
也不知道我还没得到许可
She didn't know ‭i hadn't gotten it approved.
她不知道
She just -- she didn't know.
-我懂了  -所以她不知道
- I see. - So, she didn't know
她应该事先通知霍华德什么
there was anything that she was supposed to tell Howard.
她以为克利福德已经知情了
As far as she was concerned, Cliff Main was already looped in.
你跟她说他知道了
You told her he was?
我是这么暗示的
I implied it.
所以错在我  不在她
So it's on me, not her.
她没跟我们说这些啊
She didn't say anything to us about that.
她不会说的
Well, she wouldn't.
她不想让我出丑
Sh-she wouldn't want to make me look bad.
你不能否认  这说明她缺乏判断
You have to admit this shows a lack of judgment on her part.
她了解你
She knows you.
她应该采取正确的做法
She should have known better.
你真是个混蛋
You are such an asshole.
我怎么了
Why?
我不就是指出  她信任你是个错误吗
For pointing out that her one mistake was believing in you?
天啊  能不能正确看待这件事
For Christ's sake, can we get some perspective here?
这只是个小广告
It was a simple, little commercial.
只播出了一次  仅此而已
It aired once -- that's all.
要不要我提醒你  它非常有效
And can I remind you -- it worked.
效果惊人得好
It worked like a dream.
看到你的问题了吧  吉米
See, that's your problem, Jimmy --
你认为只要结果好  手段都不重要
thinking the ends justify the means.
坏事了以后你又总是觉得震惊
And you're forever shocked when it all blows up in your face.
我犯了什么不得了的大错
What did I do that was so wrong?
你坏了规矩
you broke the rules.
你让金变成了你的从犯
‭You turned Kim into your accessory.
你让霍华德难堪  可怜的人啊
You embarrassed Howard, who -- god help him --
他居然莫名其妙地在克利福德面前为你担保
inexplicably vouched for you with Cliff Main!
克利福德和他的合伙人被你弄得像蠢货
You made Cliff and his partners look like schmucks!
还要我继续说吗
Shall I go on?!
我简直搞不懂他为什么还没炒了你
How he hasn't fired you for this positively mystifies me.
还"正确看待"
"Perspective."
你要正确地看待吗
You want perspective?
那我给你说
I'll give you mine --
你是我弟弟  我很爱你
you're my brother and I love you,
但是你就像个酒鬼
but you're like an alcoholic
拒绝承认自己有毛病
who refuses to admit he's got a problem.
现在有人给了你校车的钥匙
Now someone's given you the keys to the school bus,
我才不会让你把它开下悬崖
and I'm not gonna let you drive it off a cliff!
我们能直接说要点吗
Now, can we just get down to brass tacks here?
我要做什么才能让金回到原来岗位
What can I do to put Kim back where she belongs, huh?
你希望我退出戴维斯梅因律所吗
What -- you want me to quit Davis & Main?
那好
That's fine.
我当初就没想要那份工作
I-I never wanted that job in the first place.
跟你说不清楚
I can't get through to you.
生活不是《做交易》的那种游戏
Life is not one big game of "Let's Make a Deal"!
就是  我是蒙蒂·霍尔
Yes, it is! ‭I'm Monty Hall!
一档游戏节目  蒙蒂·霍尔曾担任主持人
二号门后面是什么
What's behind door number two?
有什么代价
What'll it take, huh?!
你想让我退出律师行业吗
You want me to quit being a lawyer?
像猩猩拿着一把机关枪
Ju-- a chimp with a machine gun --
说的是我  对吧
That's me, right, huh?!
你觉得呢
So, what do you say?
你帮金  我不当律师了
You help Kim -- I quit the law.
-成交吗  -我没那么说
- Is that a deal? - ‭I didn't say that.
你嘴上没说  但心里却这么想  是吧
No, you didn't say it, but that's what you want, right?!
所以你当初才强迫她
That's why you put the screws to Kim in the first place --
为了逼我
to squeeze me!
我没那么说  我也不会那么说
I didn't say that, ‭and I would never say that!
为什么
Why not?!
因为如果我阻碍我一个雇员的职业道路
Because if I were impeding the career of one of my employees
是为了逼你做你不愿意做的事
for the purpose of compelling you to do something against your will,
那就是敲诈
that would be extortion.
没错
Yeah. ‭
就是  那么
It would. So?
你要敲诈我吗  查克
You gonna extort me, Chuck?
那你肯定能轻而易举脱罪
It's a lead-pipe cinch you'd get away with it.
我不会告诉任何人
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
很简单  只要恢复金的职位
It's real easy -- you just set things right for Kim.
让她回原来的办公室  不再复审文件
You get her back in her office, out of doc review --
一切回归原样  我永远不当律师了
Everything back to normal, and I quit the law for good.
不再有吉米·麦吉尔先生  没了
No more Jimmy McGill, esquire -- poof!
就像没存在过
Like he never even existed.
但我得听你亲口说出来  行吗
But I need to hear the words come out of your mouth, okay?
你言而有信
‭You're a man of your word.
你是诚实的人  对吧
You're an upstanding man, right?
-天啊  吉米  -快说  查克
- For god's sake, Jimmy. ‭- Come on, chuck!
敲诈我
Extort me!
说"别干"  我就不干了
Say "quit," and I will quit,
但我得听你亲口说
but I need to hear it from your mouth!
你想让我犯下重罪吗
You want me to commit a felony...
这才是你的目的  对吧
Because that's what you'd do, right?
因为你想要相信  我其实是个伪君子
Because you want to believe that deep down, I'm some hypocrite!
那就来看看你是不是
Let's find out.
来吧  查克
Come on down, Chuck!
跟我一起在地上打滚吧
Roll around in the dirt with me!
你会实现所有的梦想
All your dreams will come true!
来  快  快说
Go on! Do it! Go on!
我不是坏人
I am not the bad guy here.
你不想当律师
You don't want to be a lawyer --
那是你和新墨西哥州律师协会的事
that's between you ‭and the New Mexico State Bar.
你想离开戴维斯梅因律所  随便你
You want to quit Davis & Main? Be my guest!
你想毁掉前途显然不需要我的帮助
You clearly don't need any help from me to tank your career.
你自己犯的事足矣
You're doing just fine on your own.
说到自毁前途  去圣达菲要一小时车程
Speaking of which, it's an hour's drive to Santa Fe.
就算你现在走
Even if you leave right now,
上班还得迟到至少二十分钟
you're still gonna be at least 20 minutes late for work --
克利福德·梅因对你的印象会更坏
another feather in your cap with Clifford Main.
怎么样
So?
我不干了
I'm not gonna do it.
怎么  你想谈判吗
What -- ‭are you negotiating now?
钱再多这也是个馊主意  对你来说
No amount of money makes this a good idea -- for you.
听着  伙计  我说了我没...
Look, man, ‭I told you that I'm not --
这样不好  因为解决不了你的实际问题
No, it's a bad move because it doesn't solve your real problem.
实际问题是什么
My real problem? What's that?
不是屠库
It's not Tuco.
而是保密
It's keeping a secret.
屠库的死会把塞拉曼加的人像苍蝇一样引来
A dead Tuco ‭draws Salamancas like flies.
贩毒集团会打探此事
The cartel noses into the business,
寻找杀害同伙的人
looks for who hit one of theirs.
你那时还能保密吗
You gonna be able to keep your secrets then?
总要付出代价
Something's got to give.
有没有你  我无所谓
With you, without you -- I don't care.
总会发生的
But something's gonna happen.
你自己也说了
You said it yourself.
你不需要他死  你需要他离开
You don't need him dead -- you need him to go away.
你是说告密吗
You mean snitch?
我打了屠库的小报告
Man, I drop a dime on Tuco,
你觉得集团会怀疑谁
who do you think the cartel looks at?
我
Me.
如果报警  我也会被抓
And if I call the cops, I get picked up, too.
我就成了已知关联人
I'm what you call a known associate.
他们把我跟屠库关在一起
So I'm locked up with Tuco,
而他正在找让他被关起来的人
who's looking for the guy that put him there.
告诉我那怎么能帮我
Tell me how that helps me.
你不用跟警察说
You won't have to talk to the cops.
任何时候都不用
You won't have to do any time.
不会死人  但屠库的问题
There's no killing, but your Tuco problem?
会解决的
It goes away.
都在这儿了
It's all there.
让他点点
Let the man count.
没问题
We're good.
那...下次再见
So, uh... till next time, huh?
屠库
Tuco.
行
Okay.
走
Go.
行
Okay.
下周再见  屠库
I'll, uh... ‭I'll see you next week, Tuco.
纳乔
Nacho.
再见  多明戈
Yeah, see you, Domingo.
他给钱还挺多
He's got good numbers.
挺拼命的
He's hustlin'.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
可靠吗
Solid?
电话
没错  我想报告一起冲突
Uh, uh, y-yes, I would like to report a fight going on
发生在伊斯莱塔大道五千街区的
at the El Michoacano restaurant in the 5000 block of
米却肯饭店
the Isleta Boulevard.
有个男人用枪威胁另一个男人
There's a man threatening another man with a gun.
看着像黑帮闹事
It looks to be some sort of gang thing.
抱歉
Oh, uh, uh, uh, sorry.
我  我只是个过路的
I-I -- I'm a passerby.
我可不想卷进去
I-I don't want to get involved.
他妈的
The fuck.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
看到什么
See what?
那个老头撞了我的车
That old man just hit my car.
你好
Hello. Oh. Hmm.
我看看
Well, let me see.
我要四号餐和鸡块  麻烦你了
Give me the number four, the pollo, por favor.
-打包带走  -好的  先生
- That's to go. - ‭Yes, sir.
你
Hey, you.
老头
Hey, gramps.
你撞到我的车了
You just hit my car.
你在跟我说话吗
Uh, you're talking to me?
马古先生来了
Check out Mr. Magoo here.
卡通人物
形象为与麦克神似的光头老者
是的  先生
Uh, y-yes, sir.
看到停在你那破车旁边的那辆车了吗
You see that car that you parked your piece of shit next to?
是我的
That's mine.
你刚刚撞到它了
You just ran into it.
不  我想我没有
No, I don't think I did.
那你是说我撒谎了
You calling me a liar?
我没这么说
Uh, no.
我也看到了
Hey. I saw it, too.
你打算否认吗
You gonna stand here and deny it?
小伙子们  我不知道该怎么跟你们说
Um, guys, um, I-I don't know what to tell you.
我不知道我撞了谁的车
I'm not aware ‭of hitting anyone's car,
但如果我真撞到了  那我道歉
but if I did... I apologize.
-所以  -六块三毛三
- So... - ‭$6.33.
不用找了
You keep the change.
谢谢
Thank you.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你给我站住
Don't you walk away from me.
老头  你最好听他的话
Hey, pops. You better listen to the man.
得了吧伙计们
Come on, guys.
咱们友好一点  行吗
Let's just keep things friendly, all right?
我不是你朋友
I ain't your friend.
你看
Look!
看到没有  你干的好事
You see that? You -- you did that.
拜托  那点东西一擦就掉了
Oh, come on. That'll buff right out.
你给我处理好
You're gonna make this all right.
否则不许走
You're not leaving until you do.
行  你有笔吗
Fine. You got a pen?
笔
A pen.
笔  留下彼此的信息  保险
A pen -- we'll exchange information, insurance.
我的保险挺全的
I have very good coverage.
保险公司会处理的
They'll take care of this.
别跟我说什么保险
I'm not messing around with insurance, ése.
我要现金
Cash.
听着  我愿意承担责任
Listen, I'm willing to accept responsibility,
但你要是不想通过保险公司
but if you're not going through insurance,
我身上只有二三十块钱
then I have maybe 20, 30 bucks on me -- that's all.
现在是你在说谎了
Kay, now you're lying to me.
我看到你的钱包了
I saw your wallet.
里面有好多钱
You got plenty in there.
把钱包拿出来
Take it out.
我们一起帮你回忆一下
Let's look together, jog your memory.
你听到他说的了
You heard him.
把钱包拿出来
Take out the wallet.
我刚兑了社保的支票
I just cashed my social security check.
我要靠这点钱支撑到月底
It's all I have till the end of the month,
我是不会把它给你的
and I am not giving it to you.
不给吗
You're not?
我愿意用正确的方式解决这件事
I offered to do this the right way.
但如果你不接受  那我也帮不了你
If you can't accept that, then I can't help you.
你们这是干什么
Aw, come on, guys.
让我用更简单的方法替你解决吧
I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
把钱包给我  也许你还能离开
Give me your wallet, and maybe you walk away from this.
我什么都不会给你的
I'm not giving you a damn thing.
不  老头
Nah, homes.
把钱包给我
Give me your wallet.
先冷静一下
Let's just stay calm here.
我流汗了吗  老东西
‭You see me sweating, bitch?
钱包
Wallet. ‭
Wallet.
钱包
差不多有四百块啊
There's like $400 here.
你还真是嘴硬啊  老家伙
You got some crazy lip on you, old man.
你的命就值四百块钱吗
Your life worth 400 bucks?
屠库  该闪人了
Hey, Tuco, time to bounce.
知道了  你先走
Yeah, go. Go.
算你今天走运  老家伙
You're...one lucky old man.
你干什么  放开我
What the hell? Let go!
放手
Let go!
Let...Let... Let go!
放手
Let go!
‭Let go!
放手
Let go!
把手举起来
Let me see your hands!
举起手来
Hands up! Now!
趴下
On the ground!
你就这点能耐
That all you got?
趴到地上
Get on the ground!
瞧你把自己搞的
Look at you.
你要去做证吗
Are you gonna have to testify?
警察亲眼目睹他犯下重罪
The cops witnessed him in the commission of a felony.
我的钱包在他口袋里
My wallet in his pocket.
再加上那把枪  他得蹲个五到十年了
Add the gun -- ‭he gets a 5-to-10 stretch.
两万五千块
$25,000.
绝对是你应得的
You definitely earned it.
只不过你本来可以更加轻松地赚上两倍
Still, you coulda gotten twice as much for 1/10 the hassle.
还可以帮这个世界清除一个垃圾
You woulda done the world a favor.
你的脸也不会像被棍子抡过一样
You wouldn't look like someone took a lead pipe to your face.
而且等屠库出来  他说不定会去找你
Plus, when Tuco gets out, maybe he comes looking for you.
说重点
Get to the point.
我只想问  你为了不开枪而这样大费周张
Just saying -- you went a long way to not pull that trigger.
到底是为什么
Why?